<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE mteval SYSTEM "mteval-xml-v1.5a.dtd">
<mteval>
<refset setid="apertium" srclang="kaz" trglang="eng" sysid="apertium" refid="zz">
<doc docid="zzz" genre="nw">
<seg id="1">WHERE IS JAMES?</seg>
<seg id="2">James and Mary are in the garden. </seg>
<seg id="3">The weather is nice today, it is very warm. </seg>
<seg id="4">But yesterday it was very cold! </seg>
<seg id="5">They could not play outside then. </seg>
<seg id="6">James and Mary love to play, they always play together in the garden in front of the big house.</seg>
<seg id="7">James is a little boy and he is six years old.</seg>
<seg id="8">The little girl is his sister, she is five years old. </seg>
<seg id="9">James has a small dog, the dog is also in the garden now. </seg>
<seg id="10">The dog likes to play with the two children. </seg>
<seg id="11">The dog is very happy now.</seg>
<seg id="12">Does Mary also have a dog? </seg>
<seg id="13">No, Mary does not have a dog, she has a cat. But the cat is in the house, the cat is sleeping.</seg>
<seg id="14">Their mother is inside the house with the cat, she looks through the window and sees James and Mary playing. </seg>
<seg id="15">James quickly runs to a big old tree, he is hiding from Mary. </seg>
<seg id="16">Do you know why? </seg>
<seg id="17">Mary is sitting and has her hands in front of her eyes. </seg>
<seg id="18">She can't see anything and she is counting. </seg>
<seg id="19">Why does she do that? </seg>
<seg id="20">And what is James doing near the tree?</seg>
<seg id="21">It is a game. </seg>
<seg id="22">When Mary has finished counting she looks around. </seg>
<seg id="23">She is searching for James: where did he go? </seg>
<seg id="24">Did you see him?</seg>
<seg id="25">Mary does not know where James is. </seg>
<seg id="26">She asks the dog: "Did you see James?". </seg>
<seg id="27">But the dog can not speak of course! </seg>
<seg id="28">So Mary gets no answer to her question. </seg>
<seg id="29">People never get an answer when they speak to dogs!</seg>
<seg id="30">Mary looks at her mother behind the window, her mother is laughing. Mary thinks that she has seen where James went: "Tell me where he is!", she says to her mother. </seg>
<seg id="31">"No Mary, I can't tell you!", she replies. </seg>
<seg id="32">Although she probably knows where he is, she does not want to tell.</seg>
<seg id="33">Mary slowly walks through the garden. </seg>
<seg id="34">She is still trying to find James. </seg>
<seg id="35">She looks under the table and under the chairs, but James is not there. </seg>
<seg id="36">She looks everywhere but she can not find James.</seg>
<seg id="37">Then she hears a sound, it is coming from behind the big old tree. Could that be James? </seg>
<seg id="38">There is the sound again! </seg>
<seg id="39">She listens carefully. </seg>
<seg id="40">It is not a bird or another animal. </seg>
<seg id="41">She can hear it well now. </seg>
<seg id="42">It must be James!</seg>
<seg id="43">Then she also sees a little hand and when she walks closer she also sees his head! </seg>
<seg id="44">She laughs and says: "I found you!". </seg>
<seg id="45">They are both happy and go to the house, it is time to eat something and drink some water!</seg>
</doc>
</refset>
</mteval>
